<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Jared Baron Panares</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Jared Baron Panares</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:24:26 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cap Write-Up</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/cap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:24:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/cap/</guid><description>Cap (Easy) Box Cap is a retired easy box from HackTheBox. It provides a light introduction into IDOR and Linux capability exploitation.
Initial Foothold Let&amp;rsquo;s start off with enumerating the ports. We can use nmap for this task.
nmap &amp;lt;TARGET-IP&amp;gt; This gives us three open ports for numbers 21, 22, and 80 for ftp, ssh, and http respectively. We can browse to the http server and we should be able to get the following webpage when we click on Security Snapshot on the left sidebar.</description></item><item><title>Shocker Write-Up</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/shocker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:15:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/shocker/</guid><description>Shocker (Easy) Box The Shocker box is an easy machine on HTB. It explores web enumeration and the ShellShock exploit.
Initial Foothold Let&amp;rsquo;s do an NMAP scan of the server:
nmap &amp;lt;TARGET-IP&amp;gt; Port 80 and Port 2222 seem to be open. A service scan on both port shows us that port 2222 is simply running an SSH service. Since we know that we&amp;rsquo;re dealing with the ShellShock exploit, we&amp;rsquo;ll set our sights on the webserver on port 80.</description></item><item><title>Lame Write-Up</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/lame/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:35:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/lame/</guid><description>Lame (Easy) Box Lame is a retired easy machine from HTB focusing on exploiting a basic vulnerability from the Samba service.
Initial Foothold &amp;amp; Escalation Let&amp;rsquo;s do a quick NMAP scan to see some open ports. An initial scan of nmap 10.129.236.188 doesn&amp;rsquo;t bring us anything. Let&amp;rsquo;s try a more stealthy approach:
sudo nmap &amp;lt;IP&amp;gt; -sS -Pn --disable-arp This gives us the following output.
If we a version scan, we see that the box has Samba version 3.</description></item><item><title>Blue Write-Up</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/blue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:25:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/blue/</guid><description>Blue (Easy) Box Blue is an easy machine on HTB. It covers the MS17_010 exploit, also known as the EternalBlue exploit.
Initial Foothold &amp;amp; Escalation According to the description, this machine is vulnerable to the EternalBlue exploit. We need to make sure that at least the SMB port 445 is open. Let&amp;rsquo;s use an NMAP scan to check what ports are open.
A quick service scan should give us some clues on the architecture and services available.</description></item><item><title>Antique Write-Up</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/antique/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 14:21:25 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/antique/</guid><description>Antique Write-Up Antique is a retired machine highlighting a known vulnerability with HP JetDirect and SNMP.
Initial Foothold The description gives us a crucial service to work with and some hints on potential weaknesses. First, let&amp;rsquo;s do a quick nmap scan. My favorite is:
sudo nmap &amp;lt;IP&amp;gt; -sS -Pn -n --disable-arp This should scan all the major ports. When it finishes, we see that port 23, the Telnet service is open.</description></item><item><title>PC (Linux) Write-Up</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/pc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 17:53:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/pc/</guid><description>PC (Linux) WriteUp PC is a retired machine focusing on gRPC, SQL injection, and privilege escalation via an RCE vulnerability. We can refer to CVE-2023-0297 for escalation.
Initial Foothold We can enumerate open ports using nmap:
sudo nmap &amp;lt;IP&amp;gt; -sS -Pn -n --disable-arp -p- I&amp;rsquo;m using a SYN scan with these options to optimize for speed. The full range of ports is also scanned. The above command yields two ports: 22 and 50051.</description></item><item><title>Crafty Write-Up</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/crafty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 22:05:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/crafty/</guid><description>Crafty (Easy) Box Overall a very fun box. Crafty is a retired box that explores a Log4j vulnerability present in a 1.16.16 Minecraft Server.
Initial Foothold Reading the description, the box has a pre-auth Log4j vulnerability. But before going into that, we should scan the ports. sudo nmap &amp;lt;IP&amp;gt; -sS -Pn -n --disable-arp -p- It looks like there are two ports open: port 80 and port 25565. Doing a quick version scan (nmap &amp;lt;IP&amp;gt; -sV -sC &amp;lt;PORT&amp;gt;) shows us that the target is running on a windows machine with a website on 80 and a Minecraft Server Version 1.</description></item><item><title>Sneaky Write-Up</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/sneaky/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 21:47:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/sneaky/</guid><description>Sneaky (Medium) Box Sneaky is a retired box focusing on IPv6 connections and buffer overflow vulnerabilities.
Initial Foothold Enumerating through the box, we see there is an HTTP server available. Let&amp;rsquo;s fuzz this and see if we can find anything. After fuzzing, we see that there is a /dev page that leads to a login screen. We can try out some payloads
When entering a ' in the Username section, we get an Internal Server Error.</description></item><item><title>Beep Write-Up</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/beep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 15:59:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/beep/</guid><description>Beep (Easy) Write-Up - HTB Beep is a retired machine released back in 2017. Upon preview, the description doesn&amp;rsquo;t really give us a lot.
Initial Foothold We can enumerate through the website using a tool like ffuf or gobuster. Using either, we&amp;rsquo;re able to map out the website. At face value though, there isn&amp;rsquo;t a lot we can find. Let&amp;rsquo;s view it with a browser. When using a browser, we get some issues viewing the site due to SSL configurations.</description></item><item><title>Websites</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/websites/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 11:28:58 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/websites/</guid><description>Habitat For Humanity THS A website for the Habitat For Humanity Travis Chapter - made during my time as officer. This website is available via: HabitatForHumanityTHS Technologies: Hugo Bootstrap HTML AgentRoll Website designed for randomizing agent selection in the game, Valorant. This is available on: AgentRoll Technologies: Svelte SvelteKit SkeletonUI/TailwindCSS Netlify CSNHS Website Website for the Computer Science National Honor Society at Travis High School. Accessible on: Computer Science Honor Society Travis Chapter Technologies: Astro Envirocate Climate change and other environmental advocacy website.</description></item><item><title>SANS Holiday Hacks '24 Write-Up</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/sans-hhc-24/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 21:06:30 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/sans-hhc-24/</guid><description>Elf Connect (Hard): Hint Summary: The high score is 50k, but that&amp;rsquo;s above the maximum amount of points. Try looking into the browser dev tools and for a variable named score. From the hint, we assume that we start at the source of the page. When we look into the HTML for the game pop-up, we can find a script tag with some JavaScript. Based on the hint, we should try looking for the variable score.</description></item><item><title>Cyber Relics: Cyberstart America</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/reviewingcyberstart/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 17:38:40 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/reviewingcyberstart/</guid><description>Anecdote CyberStart was one of the few opportunities available for high schoolers that put a focus more on learning rather than competition (it had both though). What made it different from programs such as HackTheBox were the chances to get a certification at the end of yearly program, with some criteria completed of course. From what I can recall, courses and exam attempts for at minimum the GSEC, GFACT, GCIH, and a cloud certification that I can&amp;rsquo;t remember were available.</description></item><item><title>2024 Tech Thoughts</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/predictions2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 16:45:47 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/predictions2024/</guid><description>Looking Back A lot of things happened in 2023. Just to name a few are:
The Rise and (expected) Fall of NFTs. Crypto&amp;rsquo;s continuous plummet down. Improvements in AI, pioneered by ChatGPT in general chatbot services, MidJourney in generative images, etc. A dozen more Javascript frameworks More tech layoffs And, of course, inflation But, hey&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s a new year. So let&amp;rsquo;s set some expectations at least. These are just my random tech predictions for 2024 which may or may not be supported by actual data.</description></item></channel></rss>