<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WriteUp on Jared Baron Panares</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/tags/writeup/</link><description>Recent content in WriteUp on Jared Baron Panares</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 22:05:42 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jarpiano.github.io/tags/writeup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Crafty Write-Up</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/crafty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 22:05:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/crafty/</guid><description>Crafty (Easy) Box Overall a very fun box. Crafty is a retired box that explores a Log4j vulnerability present in a 1.16.16 Minecraft Server.
Initial Foothold Reading the description, the box has a pre-auth Log4j vulnerability. But before going into that, we should scan the ports. sudo nmap &amp;lt;IP&amp;gt; -sS -Pn -n --disable-arp -p- It looks like there are two ports open: port 80 and port 25565. Doing a quick version scan (nmap &amp;lt;IP&amp;gt; -sV -sC &amp;lt;PORT&amp;gt;) shows us that the target is running on a windows machine with a website on 80 and a Minecraft Server Version 1.</description></item><item><title>Sneaky Write-Up</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/sneaky/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 21:47:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/sneaky/</guid><description>Sneaky (Medium) Box Sneaky is a retired box focusing on IPv6 connections and buffer overflow vulnerabilities.
Initial Foothold Enumerating through the box, we see there is an HTTP server available. Let&amp;rsquo;s fuzz this and see if we can find anything. After fuzzing, we see that there is a /dev page that leads to a login screen. We can try out some payloads
When entering a ' in the Username section, we get an Internal Server Error.</description></item><item><title>Beep Write-Up</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/beep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 15:59:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/beep/</guid><description>Beep (Easy) Write-Up - HTB Beep is a retired machine released back in 2017. Upon preview, the description doesn&amp;rsquo;t really give us a lot.
Initial Foothold We can enumerate through the website using a tool like ffuf or gobuster. Using either, we&amp;rsquo;re able to map out the website. At face value though, there isn&amp;rsquo;t a lot we can find. Let&amp;rsquo;s view it with a browser. When using a browser, we get some issues viewing the site due to SSL configurations.</description></item><item><title>SANS Holiday Hacks '24 Write-Up</title><link>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/sans-hhc-24/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 21:06:30 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jarpiano.github.io/blog/sans-hhc-24/</guid><description>Elf Connect (Hard): Hint Summary: The high score is 50k, but that&amp;rsquo;s above the maximum amount of points. Try looking into the browser dev tools and for a variable named score. From the hint, we assume that we start at the source of the page. When we look into the HTML for the game pop-up, we can find a script tag with some JavaScript. Based on the hint, we should try looking for the variable score.</description></item></channel></rss>